hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft now
this is going to be the last episode
that i'm wearing my chris
huh
this is going to be the last episode
that i wear my crisp
i thought i heard something wait this is
green now
does that mean it's does that mean it's
fully fixed
it's so weird that noise is so weird
does that mean that i think mumbo must
have fixed it
from your secret santa impulse oh and i
fixed your mailbox
oh my goodness now that is a
really annoying really annoying
wow look at
how many
three
stacks
of emerald block okay how do i turn it
off okay it does it does turn off
please tell me the noise stops as well
where are these note blocks this is
better than it was before
impulse you're an absolute legend
what ah what a nice gift that is really
thoughtful
and also look all the all the chests are
green
it's
of course because it's christmas
oh where's my ender chest
oh
it's exactly the same color that is a
serious gift it kind of makes the gift
that i gave iskall seem really weak now
oops that was a really cool gift thank
you so much impulse and i'm really sorry
for what's going to happen in the prank
war anyway so we've got to crack on with
today's episode now there's two main
things that i want to do the first one
is sleep because it's night time
no well there's two things i want to do
now that it is day and the first one is
i need to set a list of everything we're
going to need because i drew
on paint ms paint a very crudely drawn
image of how i kind of see the base
looking and i'm kind of going for this
stark tower modern house motif
and this is what i drew
yeah it's not it's not great but that
means we're going to need a lot of
resources and i think we can make
something really really cool in this
space
and to know what we need i'm going to
build a very quick bunker with all of
the different kinds of materials that we
might need
i also think we probably need a beacon
but
i'm not a rich man i don't have any
spare beacons so looks like i have to do
this the long way i could get a beacon
set up and then someone else could
donate their the top block for it that
might be a good idea
okay so i've got my room completely
hollowed out now it's not massive but
that's all we need because this is just
going to be where we put chests and tell
the other guys on the team
what we need in terms of resources so
that we can make our headquarters
now i'm actually going to use a bit of a
different technique here what i'm going
to do is add some sea lanterns behind it
and then some snow blocks all the way
until the very last pixel yep i just
messed up all the way to the very last
pixel and then just leave this little
bit of a slither
and that will actually give me lots of
light without having to
it's a really neat way to cover up your
lighting and if you do it in like a
bunch of different lines like this you
can create a very neat pattern that
looks very modern
oh my goodness i'm so stupid i am so
stupid i was like why isn't it doing oh
the sea lanterns melt the snow
oh my goodness i'm so
stupid sometimes
i've just been placing all this snow and
ruining it
oh my goodness at least i can try and
save a little bit here oh i feel like
such an idiot right now
[Laughter]
i could have very easily gone on for a
long time without realizing what i was
doing i was like i'm sure that i've done
these before what's going on well this
hasn't gone entirely to plan so far but
this is the general idea and then i'm
thinking that we have the chests that
run along these sides and then i have
like an entrance and exit here with a
giant g in the middle to symbolize the g
team or some people suggested that we
call ourselves g-force now that is a
movie
but i think that is also a pretty cool
name then it's not too late to change
the name i'm not
people liked my joke about having g in
the name so i i don't think anyone would
mind if we changed it
so this is going to be like the little
mass storage collection system that
we're going to make now i have actually
got enough chest oh that is weird to see
isn't it red green
now i've actually not brought enough
chests with me and there's actually
quite a lot of things that i haven't
brought with me however you can kind of
see this place coming together it is
just like a modern bunkery type thing my
main priority now is i need a lot more
snow and i need to go and grab some
chests now can i sleep before that
creeper sees me and blows me up
yes
[Laughter]
very very close
oh man that was a proper danger sleep
right there i'm glad i took the risk i
almost bailed i almost bailed on it okay
so i need to go over to the christmas
district actually and it's rather
fitting as it is christmas eve happy
holidays to everybody that celebrates on
the 24th and happy holidays for everyone
that celebrates on the 25th and happy
holidays to everybody that doesn't
celebrate at all so we're going to go
over to the festive district to go and
check out where we can get the snow
cause i think they will have lots of
snow guns there and i haven't actually
checked this out since it started being
made so this will be a really good
opportunity to take a look at what's
been made at all
oh my goodness this looks awesome
wow
it's a shame that it wasn't finished in
time for
christmas eve but i mean look at this
you you don't need to imagine too much
to see what this would all look like
finished but oh my goodness this is
awesome giant tree
really nicely decorated trees here
snow everywhere little village oh this
is this is so cool
little cars there's the secret santa
sleigh
oh man this is this has got me in the
christmas spirit
well and truly i wish it was finished
but it's really good i kind of feel bad
i didn't really contribute anything
oh there's even a little play going on
oh this is the cutest thing and tango's
king for some reason look at this
they're so organized like they've got
things rough look at all the red blocks
all the wood
blue blocks cobble ah it's absolutely
brilliant wait do you see what i see i
are they who is this whose stuff is this
it's not labelled
are they poultry man
i think they
they might be portraying man i mean
that's conclusive evidence right there
whoever this is have you have you ever
seen whoever this is and poultry man in
the same room
didn't think so oh yeah i came here for
snow
let's go and find that snow golem there
he is so you stand here
and
you just click and hold i'm getting
really bad flashbacks to when i had to
make the infinity room i thought i'd
never have to do this again
okay that should do it
and that's pretty much the only use i've
had for the festive district but this is
really nice this is actually really
really nice
i think the prank war might have
slightly gotten in the way
of the festive district
there we go that looks pretty good it's
not it's not it's not the best maybe i
could do a few more things to brighten
this up but
at the end of the day this is just a
temporary storage place so i don't think
there's any point in getting super
attached to it in any sense because i
think this won't really last that long
this is just a place for us to gather
everything that we need
and then all i need to do is put in what
is in each one at this point i'm totally
guessing what we need but if we're going
for like a tony stark tower i think
we're going to need very similar blocks
to the ones that i have in my base which
means
white concrete a lot is going to mean a
lot of cyan terracotta a lot and it's
going to mean a lot of cyan stained
glass
as well
so those things plus some extras just
trying to think what we might need
ah stone
if we're going to make some sort of base
like you know an actual base for it to
sit on a foundation that is we're going
to need a lot of rocks to be able to do
that that's a pretty good start but i'm
like the only other person apart from
zombie glio that's on and like i don't
think any gathering is going to happen
over the holidays but hopefully after
christmas we can all sink our teeth in
and get cracking on this build so here's
kind of how i see our team functioning
i'm gonna make sure that we build
something really epic i'm hoping that
tango can provide us with some of the
farms that we might need you know like
uh some super smelters maybe a food farm
that kind of thing because i don't think
we really want to use too much of our
own resources because
this sort of thing is very expensive so
we got to like get together we got to
make our own little farms within the
base
and protect them from the other team so
i'm hoping that tango can and iskall
actually iskall's very good at redstone
i'm hoping all of us together can
make some excellent farms ah i've just
finished it took well over an hour but
i've cleared out everything here the
idea is that we don't really need to
protect it right because there's a
massive ceasefire as you can see the big
white flag over there
but i don't really want them to see what
we're doing or go snooping around at the
same time like if we just have
everything up here they're gonna see
what we're up to so i've created this
little room and this is the final
product so this is the very first g room
i've just put g i i kind of like the
name g4 so i'm not gonna lie so i've got
all these chests as i said earlier about
what we might need to collect but i've
also created some bunk beds which i'm
actually going to use now because i need
to make it day
and i should probably leave a couple of
signs i've also got a couple of water
elevators going in and out i think this
is a really good start we can really
build from here and then i've got like a
little feature wall here with those
little uh holes in there and it looks
really cool i think everything here fits
rather well i wish i had some end rods
but
you know i've i've used quite a lot of
resources to make this thing so
hopefully now we can get the team
together
and add everything else now i'm going to
add an ender chest here
and that should complete
the very first thing that we're going to
do now i want to go and complete my
avery that i started last episode
i should really use the nether more it's
much quicker
what
oh no
no
don't kill me please oh my goodness no
no no no no no
something
something's gone
something's gone really wrong
with the nether portal
i don't know what's up
but that
holy heck what is going on hold on i
want to go and see is that is it just
like a one-time fluke
no no we're in the end wait we're in
like a
end
what we're in like a end nether hybrid
can i fly
oh my goodness we're in the nether
but we're also in the end
what on earth oh my goodness this is
like the coolest thing
this is like
something has really gone wrong
with
the hermitcraft server
[Laughter]
oh
oh no
i need to go back
i need to find my way back hey there's
something i recognize oh they're okay
we're in the nether hub now
what the heck is going on
wait this is
so confusing
now i assume that this will get fixed
but at the same time
this is awesome i've never seen this is
like the far lands 2.0 how has this
happened
i think we should find our nearest
portal
and get the heck out of here
if we travel through the netherlands we
might be able to find a portal out of
here something's gone really really
wrong
just don't look at them
all right i think we're just gonna
pretend like nothing is wrong and we're
gonna go and make
a happy place
i'm kind of curious what happens if i go
through my portal now
yep
still here
this is so strange
okay well um as we do on hermitcraft and
we're just going to pretend uh nothing's
wrong
wait what oh come on
i think we can conclude that the nether
is fully out of action for now now up at
the top of my base here
in this very last section i started
making my avery that's what i want to
continue making today
no how did you guys get outside
how was that
did
he was right here
i see they must have just teleported
outside
and hey there's a chicken in here we've
got all the birds the parrots are so
much cuter
so my idea here is to create sort of
like a bowl of grass here
and then i will add in a load of trees
and because i've got so much height i've
got a lot of opportunity to make big big
trees
i just hope i've got enough time
you know what it already feels really
nice in here that that ceiling is not
great because i haven't done any
interior but oh my i'm really enjoying
the look of this this is like a really
tranquil space already there's kind of a
lot you can do here like you can place
some melons around like all the
different colors are this is gonna be
really nice
i don't really know exactly what i'm
gonna do with this room but
it's just relaxing i guess i'm gonna do
my best to hide the lighting by placing
some sea lanterns and then adding a
carpet over the top a green carpet
because the green carpet will actually
look a bit like moss and it should fit
in quite nicely
and it'll stop things spawning up here
as well which is a never-ending problem
one thing i think i would like to create
here though is a pond like some water
feature so i might have to take all this
out
to make it i don't think it'll be too
big but it should be big enough to put a
couple of fish in
adding some stones around to be like
pebbles that'll make this seem really
nice as well and of course i need to
plan out a couple of really big trees
which i think should start about
here and maybe one slightly off to the
center
here it's actually
quite a lot taller than i thought so
these trees might have to be very very
big to make use of the space
or it can just be eye level i don't
really mind i need to go down and get
myself a little fish or two you guys
will do just fine i wasn't particularly
inventive with these names so we've got
uh we've got fish name and fish
so we'll leave those two to get
acquainted with their new pond
and now we just gonna make some nice
trees
so this is the progress that i've made
so far i think i'm pretty happy with how
it looks on the floor looks very foresty
very tranquil but i'm gonna have to add
trees and i think i'm gonna have to add
like a medium-sized some large ones here
and here and really fill this out to the
best of my ability maybe even make like
little patches of green grass floating
here or something along those lines to
make use of the height i'm not entirely
sure but unfortunately i can't spend
much more time doing this because it's
nearly the end of the episode i am
desperately running out of time to make
this one today
we need to do one more thing before the
end of the episode
then we go
even land in the water
ah
yes i've seen a few people
say that
they know who poultry man is but nobody
knows who poultry man is because it's
certainly not green
[Laughter]
oh wait
i didn't even notice this
what is this
there's no signs
i didn't make this green or poultry man
did not make this does anyone know what
this is it's like a super computer this
is awesome if anyone knows where this
came from wait how did they get access
to the poultry cave oh or the coop maybe
we should call this place the coop
how on earth did they find my secret my
super secret hidey hole if this is a
super computer i'm gonna use this to
make some like poultry vlogs or
something also why am i eating chicken
that's probably the the worst thing that
i could be eating anyway
we need to get somebody back because
someone did not build something in my
base and i've left it a few days and i
know that
certain someone that may have not built
something in my base won't be around for
a while so this gives it a good
opportunity to catch up i just realized
how bad it is that the nether is all
messed up there's a lot of stuff in
there not only was there a lot of work
but like my elytra's running out and i
use the pigman xp thing like every day
so i'm a little bit scared i hope it
gets fixed soon i'm gonna have to be
conservative now i'm gonna show mumbo
how we do it for real
i'm going to show mumbo how we chicken
for real oh my goodness there's still
chickens here from the chicken bomb
unbelievable anyway what if we just
change we go inside here
and we create a dispenser machine
i don't think mumbo actually goes in
here so this could be pretty good so
this is pretty simple i think my
redstone ability is not great but every
time an item goes through here
it then activates that as it goes into
the dispenser so all i need to do
is
link this up to the dispenser itself
now i think it's time for mumbo to get a
taste of his own medicine so you guys
need to tell him poultry man did
definitely didn't build something in his
face poultry man not green
not not green poultry man poultry man
did not build something in his did not
build something in mumbo's base you've
got to go and tell him exactly the same
way he got me we're going to get him as
well i think i've got it
i think i've got it so that was much
easier than i thought and i did i did
look it up i'm not going to lie i had to
look up a way to do it so there's 10
eggs in the dispenser that powers this
just enough to give it that and then
if one more falls through now these are
these little chickens are not quite
ready but if one egg falls through
there we go you can hear it going off
it's dispensing the eggs now i hope that
these are actually
producing some chickens i don't know if
they do if they're dispensed
they must do surely they must do well
there's one way to find out let's plug
it full of eggs so what if we plug them
in here like this there we go so let's
plug these in
we'll see that it's dispensing up yep
it's definite it's definitely producing
the chickens
not a very good rate yeah there we go
okay cool so now all we have to do
is load up
this up here with more little chickies
so when these guys grow
they will
they will cause the same mayhem
that mumbo caused green
all right
and i'm afraid that's all we have time
for today so thank you very much for
watching everyone i hope you enjoyed
this episode and i hope you all have a
fantastic holiday season whether you
celebrate or not thank you very much for
watching everyone and good
bye don't forget to tell mumbo that
poultry man may or may not have built
something definitely didn't build
something definitely didn't
[Laughter]